Guide to the Life Savers promotional archive, 1924-1953 and undated RL.11766
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Life Savers promotional archive
1924-1953 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11766
1.0 Linear Feet
Life Savers are a brand of hard and soft candies first produced in 1912, currently owned by Mars. Collection consists of approximately 150 items: matted advertising, display and promotional designs; black and white photographs; and negatives that depict a variety of campaigns to market Life Savers in early and mid-century United States. Included are photographs of models in various poses; candy displays (including displays of competitors such as Curtiss's Baby Ruth/Butterfinger and Pine Bros. Glycerin Tablets); celebrities posing with the candy in endorsement or other promotional campaign; street vendors (Life Savers Sampler Girls); and images of placements of the candy in film productions. Celebrities include Ann Rutherford, Edgar Bergen, George McManus, George Raft, Jack Benny, Lou Costello, Maggie Jiggs and Virginia Mayo. Images produced by a number of prominent photographers and agencies, including Acme Newspictures, Ewing Galloway, General Outdoor, Guy Gillette, Hyman Fink, Keystone View, McArthur Advertising, Shigeta-Wright, and the Vacuum Candy Machinery Company. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Designs and layouts; Photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Life Savers are a brand of hard and soft candies. Formula and design invented by Clarence Crane 1912. Formula sold to Edward Noble 1913. Brand acquired by Beech Nut 1956; E.R. Squibb 1968; Nabisco 1981; Wrigley's 2004; Mars 2008. Source: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Life_Savers.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Life Savers promotional archive was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Foote, Cone & Belding, Inc. records
J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm microfilm as-broadcast scripts
Outdoor Advertising Association of America. Poster Designs
Roy Lightner collection of antique advertisements
W.W. Parleir papers
Woolworth Spring Convention display photographs.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of approximately 150 items: matted advertising, display and promotional designs; black and white photographs; and negatives that depict a variety of campaigns to market Life Savers in early and mid-century United States. Included are photographs of models in various poses; candy displays (including displays of competitors such as Curtiss's Baby Ruth/Butterfinger and Pine Bros. Glycerin Tablets); celebrities posing with the candy in endorsement or other promotional campaign; street vendors (Life Savers Sampler Girls); and images of placements of the candy in film productions. Celebrities include Ann Rutherford, Edgar Bergen, George McManus, George Raft, Jack Benny, Lou Costello, Maggie Jiggs and Virginia Mayo. Images produced by a number of prominent photographers and agencies, including Acme Newspictures, Ewing Galloway, General Outdoor, Guy Gillette, Hyman Fink, Keystone View, McArthur Advertising, Shigeta-Wright, and the Vacuum Candy Machinery Company. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Design; Advertising -- United States; Advertising photography; Celebrities -- United States -- 20th century; Commercial photography; Endorsements in advertising; Photographers -- United States; Product placement in mass media -- United States -- History; Sales personnel; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; General Outdoor Advertising Company; Mars, Incorporated; Keystone View Company.; Acme Newspictures (New York, N.Y.)
- Designs and layouts, 1932-1934 and undated; 1
  - Advertising layouts, 1934 and undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Factory scenes, undated (Box 1)
  - Models and poses, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Models and poses, 1932 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Product placement designs, undated (Box 1)
- Photographs, 1924-1953 and undated; 2
  - Advertisements and displays, 1945-1949 and undated (Box 2)
  - Celebrities, film placements, 1949-1950 and undated (Box 2)
  - Factory scenes, 1947-1953 and undated (Box 2)
  - Factory scenes, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Original photography, 1940s (Box 2)
  - Sampler Girls (sales personnel), 1924-1950 (Box 2)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 2)